

### Profile

Passionate software developer with an experience of 2+ years in IT and software industry. Knowledgeable in user interface, testing, and debugging processes. Proficient in an assortment of technologies, including JavaScript, React, Node.js, Python, MongoDB and SQL. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate as part of a productive team.

# Employment History

## Front End Developer (React.js) at Naico ITS, Kochi

March 2020 — October 2021

- Implemented and updated application modules under the direction of Senior Software Developers.
- Effectively coded software changes and alterations based on specific design specifications.
- Assist in the design, coding and unit testing of technical solutions.
- Developing code as per client requirements and performing minor bug fixes.
- Worked in front-end of Health Care project using React.

## Back End Developer (Node.js) at Factweavers Technologies, Kochi January 2022 — July 2022

- Worked on rewriting an older version of nodejs based health care app to a newer version along with utilizing microservices for optimizing performance.
- Experience in RESTful API design and development.
- Experience with relational database(PostgreSQL).

#### ReactJS Developer at iLeaf Solutions, Kochi

August 2022 — October 2022

- Worked closely with the development team to implement the front end of a data collection project.
- Currently working on designing and implementing a Data Management System.
- Worked with back end development team to integrate API with front end.
- Responsible for software maintenance across the codebase.

#### Education

Master of Computer Applications, Federal Institute of Science & Technology, Kochi

August 2017 — June 2019

#### **Details**

Kochi India +918921762662, +918136892662 jissmon476@gmail.com

#### Websites & Social Links

Linkedin Github Portfolio

#### **Skills**

HTML, CSS & Bootstrap

JavaScript

**TypeScript** 

ReactJS

Redux

Node.js

Express.js

Axios

SQL

PostgreSQL

MongoDB

RESTful API

Version Control Systems (Git, SVN)

Agile & Scrum

TDD Tools (Jasmine and

Karma)

**Code Versioning** 

Tools(Github, Bitbucket)

Front End Development Tools(NPM, Babel, ESLint)

## Languages

English

Malayalam

# Bachelor of Computer Applications, De Paul Institute of Science & Technology, Kochi

July 2014 — May 2017

**Interest** 

Software Development Data Science Machine Learning

# **★** Personal & Academic Projects

**News Classification** 

**Duration: 3 Months** 

Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Scikit-Learn,

Nltk.

Github Link: https://github.com/jisshub/news-classification

Objective: Build a model to predict the category of news article.

**Django Course Registration App** 

Duration: 1 Month

Technologies Used: Python, Django, SQLite

Github Link: https://github.com/jisshub/students-courses-app

Objective: Allows people to register for IT & software related programs.

**Algerian Forest Fires Prediction** 

July 2022

Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, Seaborn, Flask.

Github Link:

https://github.com/jisshub/Algerian-Forest-Fires-Prediction

Heroku Link: https://forest-fires-classification.herokuapp.com/

Objective: Build a model that takes in the detected fires dataset learns

and detects future fires based on certain weather report.

**MERN Workout Buddy App** 

August 2022

Technologies Used: React, Node, MongoDB.

Objective: Develop an app to track the exercises we do.

Github Link: https://github.com/jisshub/mern-stack-app

**Boston House Price Prediction** 

September 2022

Technologies Used: Python, Pandas, Linear Regression, Scikit-Learn,

Seaborn, Flask, Heroku, Dockers.

Github Link:

https://github.com/jisshub/Boston-House-Price-Prediction

Heroku Link: https://boston-house-price-pred-app.herokuapp.com/

Objective: Build a model for predicting the house price by taking a set

of features that describes a house in boston.

Courses

## Python Web Development, Luminar Technoloab

September 2019 — December 2019

# Nodejs API With Express & MongoDB, Udemy

August 2021

# SQL for Data Science, Udemy

April 2019

# Full Stack Data Science, iNeuron.ai

November 2021 — Present

## **★** Hobbies

# **Reading Books**

Favourite Books:

- The Anarchy: The East India Company, Corporate Violence, and the Pillage of an Empire
- An Era of Darkness: The British Empire in India